<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet
        href="/usr/share/web/xsl/yagsbook/html/yagsbook.xsl"
        type="text/xsl"?>

<article>
    <header>
        <title>Cairn Hills</title>
        <tagline>Habisfern</tagline>
        
        <author>
            <fullname>Samuel Penn</fullname>
            <email>sam@bifrost.demon.co.uk</email>
        </author>
        
        <cvsinfo>
            <revision>$Revision$</revision>
            <date>$Date$</date>
        </cvsinfo>
        
        <license>
            <year>2002</year>
            <holder>Samuel Penn</holder>
            <url></url>
            <text>
                The GNU Free Documentation License.
            </text>
        </license>
        
        <campaign>
            <date>Spring, 731</date>
        </campaign>
        
        <style name="module">
            <hint name="suppressNumbering" value="true"/>
        </style>
    </header>

    <front/>
    <back/>
    
    <body>
        <sect1>
            <title>The Cairn Hills</title>

            <para>
                Politically, the Cairn Hills are part of the Shire of
                Northwood, and have no significance as far as borders
                and ownership is concerned. Several hundreds border
                onto the region, but due to the low population found
                actually within the hills, little effort is made to
                police the area.
            </para>
            
            <para>
                Geographically, the region is more notable. The hills
                rise up from the plains to the east, and can be seen
                from most of the trade routes that link the north and
                the south. The western parts are covered in thick
                woodland, and the south descends into the tangled
                darkness of Meam's Wood, which officially has a
                population of zero, though unofficially is home to
                various outlaw bands and numerous fell beasts.
            </para>
            
            <para>
                The hills are chalk, with an average height of two                         to three hundred metres. The tallest hills are in the
                northwest, where the occasional 400m peak can be found.
            </para>

            <sect2>
                <title>Folk lore</title>

                <para>
                    The Cairn Hills are well renowed in folk lore for
                    being a place of unnatural happenings. To the early
                    tribes, these lands were sacred, and still sometimes
                    host religious ceremonies held by small cults.
                </para>
                
                <sect3>
                    <title>The Riders</title>
                    
                    <para>
                        One of the most common legends about the hills
                        is that of the    Riders - warrior horsemen who,
                        it is said, are doomed to ride eternally, never
                        setting foot on land. When the lands were ruled
                        by barbarians, there was a king called Enstig
                        Longhair, who ruled the lands around the Cairn
                        Hills.
                    </para>
                    
                    <para>
                        Legend has it that he married a woman of the                             otherlands, a fey beauty who spirited him and
                        his huscarls off to her home to live for
                        eternity. Every now and again, he and his men
                        return to patrol their original kingdom. If they
                        ever set a foot on the earth, then    the years
                        they have cheated will catch up with them, and
                        they will die.
                    </para>
                    
                    <para>
                        The Riders are reported about every 10 years.
                    </para>
                </sect3>
                
                <sect3>
                    <title>The Last Elder</title>
                    
                    <para>
                        It is generally thought that the Cairn Hills
                        were considered sacred by the Druidic tribes
                        who lived here before the coming of the people
                        of Rorn, and that many secrets of the Elders
                        are buried beneath some of the hills.
                    </para>
                    
                    <para>
                        The most common story about the Elders is that
                        the last of them was killed here in the final
                        years of the war against the Druids. The Elder
                        was slain above his temple, which was burnt
                        and buried to keep its dark secrets from preying
                        eyes. Many people have looked for it, though
                        none have conclusively found it. Some say that
                        it is beneath Ashek's Tower, whilst others
                        think that it is a different place.
                    </para>
                    
                    <para>
                        The truth may never be known, especially since
                        the people of the Cairn Hills are not the only
                        ones to claim that the last of the Elders was
                        slain near their home.
                    </para>
                </sect3>
            </sect2>
        </sect1>

        <sect1>
            <title>Rorn's Vale</title>

            <para>
                Rorn's Vale is a typical hundred town, with a population
                of about four hundred. The thegn here, Berdun, is an
                old, somewhat bitter man who now lives alone, the rest
                of his family having either died or left him. His mood
                has infected much of the village. The reeve is Jarn
                Hastikson, also a priest of Ashek.
            </para>

            <para>
                Jarn is old, mad, and somewhat incoherent, which fits his
                position as a priest of Ashek perfectly. During his saner
                moments he can be very perceptive and crafty however. He
                is a wizard, of quite a bit of power, though has
                forgotton almost as much as he has learned, His
                specialities are men, animals and weather.
            </para>

            <para>
                The most respected member of the community is Jangi,
                daughter of Jarn, though no-one knows her mother. She
                turned up thirty years ago in Jarn's house, with Jarn
                claiming he was her father. She is unmarried. She has
                black hair, green eyes and very pale skin. When she was
                12, she went missing for several days, and when she was
                found she had tatoos across her chest, left shoulder and
                back, and wouldn't say what had happened.
            </para>
            
            <sect2>
                <title>People</title>
                
                <para>
                    Rorn's Vale is quite a way off the major trade
                    routes, and needs to be pretty much self supporting
                    wherever possible. It is a focal point for those
                    who live in and around the Cairn Hills.
                </para>
                
                <character name="Berdun">
                    <description>
                        <race>Human</race>
                        <gender>Male</gender>
                        <age>45</age>
                        
                        <short>
                            Middle aged man with dark unkempt hair.
                        </short>
                    </description>
                    
                    <attributes size="5">
                        <attribute name="strength" score="3"/>
                        <attribute name="stamina" score="3"/>
                        <attribute name="agility" score="3"/>
                        <attribute name="dexterity" score="2"/>
                        <attribute name="perception" score="3"/>
                        <attribute name="intelligence" score="3"/>
                        <attribute name="charisma" score="2"/>
                        <attribute name="will" score="3"/>
                    </attributes>
                        
                    <passions>
                        <passion name="Bravery" score="4"/>
                        <passion name="Ego" score="3"/>
                        <passion name="Restraint" score="4"/>
                        <passion name="Temperence" score="2"/>
                    </passions>
                        
                    <skills>
                        <group name="Talents" type="talents">
                            <skill name="Athletics" score="2"/>
                            <skill name="Awareness" score="3"/>
                            <skill name="Brawl" score="4"/>
                            <skill name="Charm" score="4"/>
                            <skill name="Guile" score="3"/>
                            <skill name="Sleight" score="1"/>
                            <skill name="Stealth" score="2"/>
                            <skill name="Throw" score="4"/>
                        </group>
                            
                        <group name="Knowledges" type="knowledge">
                            <skill name="Area lore" score="2"/>
                            <skill name="Folk lore" score="2"/>
                            <skill name="Law" score="2"/>
                        </group>
                            
                        <group name="Languages" type="language">
                            <skill name="Speak Rornic" score="4"/>
                        </group>
                        
                        <group name="Combat" type="skills">
                            <skill name="Weapon and shield" score="5"/>
                        </group>
                        
                        <group name="Misc" type="skills">
                            <skill name="Farming" score="3"/>
                            <skill name="Trade" score="3"/>
                        </group>
                    </skills>
                    
                    <advantages>
                        <advantage name="Weakness (alcohol)"/>
                        <advantage name="Heavy drinker" score="+2"/>
                    </advantages>
                </character>
                
                <character name="Jangi">
                    <description>
                        <race>Human</race>
                        <gender>Female</gender>
                        <age>27</age>
                        
                        <short>
                            Good looking woman with long dark hair.
                        </short>
                    </description>
                        
                    <attributes size="5">
                        <attribute name="strength" score="2"/>
                        <attribute name="stamina" score="3"/>
                        <attribute name="agility" score="3"/>
                        <attribute name="dexterity" score="3"/>
                        <attribute name="perception" score="3"/>
                        <attribute name="intelligence" score="3"/>
                        <attribute name="charisma" score="4"/>
                        <attribute name="will" score="4"/>
                    </attributes>
                        
                    <passions>
                        <passion name="Bravery" score="4"/>
                        <passion name="Ego" score="5"/>
                        <passion name="Restraint" score="3"/>
                        <passion name="Temperence" score="6"/>
                    </passions>
                        
                    <skills>
                        <group name="Talents" type="talents">
                            <skill name="Athletics" score="4"/>
                            <skill name="Awareness" score="3"/>
                            <skill name="Brawl" score="2"/>
                            <skill name="Charm" score="5"/>
                            <skill name="Guile" score="3"/>
                            <skill name="Sleight" score="3"/>
                            <skill name="Stealth" score="3"/>
                            <skill name="Throw" score="2"/>
                        </group>
                            
                        <group name="Knowledges" type="knowledge">
                            <skill name="Area lore" score="2"/>
                            <skill name="Folk lore" score="3"/>
                            <skill name="Law" score="1"/>
                        </group>
                            
                        <group name="Languages" type="language">
                            <skill name="Speak Rornic" score="4"/>
                        </group>
                        
                        <group name="Misc" type="skills">
                            <skill name="Handicraft" score="4"/>
                            <skill name="Brewing" score="2"/>
                            <skill name="Farming" score="2"/>
                            <skill name="Trade" score="2"/>
                        </group>
                    </skills>
                    
                    <advantages>
                        <advantages name="Appearance" score="+1"/>
                </character>
            </sect2>
            
            <sect2>
                <title>History</title>
            </sect2>
        </sect1>

        <sect1>
            <title>The Cairns</title>

            <para>
                Spread across the southern hills in a rough east - west
                line are the cairns. There are about four dozen in all,
                though legend has it that their true number cannot be
                accurately counted. There are six major cairns, which
                each have extensive crypts beneath them. The rest are
                single caves, or simple mounds containing no more than
                one or two bodies.
            </para>

            <sect2>
                <title>The Great Six</title>

                <sect3>
                    <title>The Round Chamber</title>

                    <para>
                        A tunnel goes directly into a steep hillside -
                        getting to it can be difficult. There is a large
                        round chamber within, with some smaller chambers
                        off from the main one.
                    </para>
                </sect3>

                <sect3>
                    <title>Ecbrit's Cairn</title>

                    <para>
                        The Ecbrit in question was a recent thegn who
                        had himself buried here along with the other
                        warriors. His tormented ghost is often seen near
                        to the site. It is a simple mound, but has the
                        most extensive tunnel system of any of the                                 cairns.
                    </para>
                </sect3>

                <sect3>
                    <title>The White Man</title>

                    <para>
                        A chalk man with spear is carved into the top of
                        this hill. There is an entrance beneath the
                        man's feet.
                    </para>
                </sect3>

                <sect3>
                    <title>Stone Shield Hill</title>

                    <para>
                        A mound fifteen metres long, six metres wide and
                        some three metres tall. It's sides are ringed                             with flat, circular stones, and there is a stone
                        archway leading into a narrow chamber at the                             east end.
                    </para>
                </sect3>

                <sect3>
                    <title>Corpse Hill</title>

                    <para>
                        A very large artificial hill.
                    </para>
                </sect3>

                <sect3>
                    <title>Four Barrows</title>

                    <para>
                        Four barrows aligned facing towards each other.
                    </para>
                </sect3>
            </sect2>
        </sect1>

        <sect1>
            <title>Ashek's Tower</title>

            <para>
                The strangest feature of the hills is that of Ashek's
                Tower. It rises 25m above ground level as a steep hill,
                the top of which opens into a rocky shaft which drops
                about 50m almost straight down to a small, subterranean
                lake.
            </para>
        </sect1>
        
        <sect1>
            <title>Meam's Wood</title>
            
            <para>
                To the south of the Cairn Hills, lays an area of thick
                wood and marsh known as Meam's Wood. It is a place that
                is avoided by common folk, since the place has a
                reputation that exceeds that of the Cairns in
                unpleasentness.
            </para>
            
            <para>
                It is believed that Meam sought refuge here after he
                had been driven out by his father, and that the place
                picked up on his poisonous, hate filled thoughts and made
                them real. Most of the stories of strange beasts that
                dwell here now are just stories, but not all of them.
                The occasional beast is caught or killed on the edge of
                the region, but darker things are said to dwell in the
                deepest parts.
            </para>
            
            <sect2>
                <title>Geography</title>
                
                <para>
                    There is little in the way of a definite border to
                    the north. The Cairn Hills become wooded in their
                    southernmost extremities, and gradually drop down
                    towards the marshes. At some point, the woods
                    thicken enough for the fell beasts to be found
                    hunting, but the exact point changes from year to
                    year.
                </para>
                
                <para>
                    The marshland is not particularly deep or
                    unpleseant - there are worse marshes to be found.
                    They are however quite extensive, and the addition
                    of the creatures that dwell there is what makes
                    them notable. Most the the marshland is also wooded,
                    though the woods are somewhat lighter than in the
                    dryer parts of Meam's Wood.
                </para>
            </sect2>
            
            <sect2>
                <title>Men of the Wood</title>
                
                <para>
                    Despite the hardships to be had living here, for
                    those with disagreements with the Queen's Justice,
                    it can be a better home than elsewhere. It is
                    an accepted fact that anyone who dwells here is
                    beyond the reach of the law, since few are willing
                    to persue far into the place.
                </para>
                
                <para>
                    Because of this, there are a number of outlaw bands
                    who have made a home here. They survive by hunting,
                    raiding surrounding villages and caravans, or
                    stealing from each other. There is little in the way
                    of cooperation between any of the groups.
                </para>
            </sect2>
        </sect1>
    </body>
</article>
 
#ÿ