<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet
        href="/usr/share/web/xsl/yagsbook/html/yagsbook.xsl"
        type="text/xsl"?>

<article>
    <header>
        <title>The Troll Watch</title>
        <tagline>Habisfern</tagline>
        
        <author>
            <fullname>Samuel Penn</fullname>
            <email>sam@bifrost.demon.co.uk</email>
        </author>
        
        <cvsinfo>
            <revision>$Revision$</revision>
            <date>$Date$</date>
        </cvsinfo>
        
        <license>
            <year>2002</year>
            <holder>Samuel Penn</holder>
            <url></url>
            <text>
                The GNU Free Documentation License.
            </text>
        </license>
        
        <campaign>
            <date>Spring, 731</date>
        </campaign>
        
        <style name="module">
            <hint name="suppressNumbering" value="true"/>
        </style>
    </header>
    
    <body>
        <sect1>
            <title>The Troll Watch</title>

            <para>
                Stretched along the eastern side of the shire of Merkia
                is a region of thick woodland known as the Troll Watch.
                It is said by some that the place is named so, since any
                who travel within it must always watch for trolls. Others
                say that it is the trolls that watch mankind, reporting
                back to a king of trolls deep in the woods.
            </para>
            
            <para>
                In any case, trolls are common. They occasionaly raid
                beyond the woods, but for the most part prefere the
                darkness of the woods. Several forays into the woods to
                hunt down and wipe out the trolls have been made, but
                all have met with disaster. It may be that there is a 
                controlling mind behind the actions of the trolls, for
                if seriously threatened, they begin to act together
                for the defence of their home.
            </para>
            
            <para>
                The most common trolls here are the hairy kind.
            </para>
        </sect1>
        
        <sect1>
            <title>Old Castle</title>
            
            <para>
                Hidden in the western parts of the Troll Watch are
                the ruins of an old hill fort, built during the 
                migration wars.
            </para>
            
            <sect2>
                <title>Inhabitants</title>
                
                <para>
                    A small group of outlaws currently have residence
                    here. They are left alone by the Kingdom, since
                    there are far worse things living in the Troll
                    Watch than this lot, who mostly keep to themselves.
                </para>
                
                <para>
                    Penda the Mouse is in charge. A small, wiry man
                    who's appearance gave him his name. He is a
                    competent leader however, as well as being a
                    dangerous killer and a priest of Tharos.
                </para>
            </sect2>
        </sect1>
    </body>
</article>
 
#ÿ